So far in this lesson we've talked about why we debate and we've learned some basic vocabulary that
到目前为止，在本课中，我们已经讨论了为什么要辩论，并且我们已经学习了一些基本词汇
we can use to talk about debates.
我们可以用来谈论辩论。
Then we went into some phrases some expressions we can use when we're having debates to poke holes in
然后我们进入了一些短语，一些我们在辩论时可以使用的表达方式来戳洞
a case or someone else's argument.
一个案例或别人的论点。
Then we looked at a couple more we can use when we want to concede a point as a way to shift the focus
然后我们查看了更多当我们想要承认一点时可以使用的方法来转移焦点
away from maybe a weak point we have or make what we call a counterpoint.
远离我们可能拥有的弱点或做出我们所谓的对位。
Now we're going to look at a real example.
现在我们来看一个真实的例子。
We're going to look at a debate topic and then we're going to look at two sides.
我们将看一个辩论主题，然后我们将看两个方面。
And we're going to see if we can actually use some of the things that we learned earlier on in this
我们将看看我们是否可以真正使用我们之前在本文中学到的一些东西
lesson.
课。
So our topic will be video games particularly violent video games violent video games means video games
所以我们的话题将是电子游戏特别是暴力电子游戏暴力电子游戏意味着电子游戏
with violence maybe that's fighting maybe that's killing for example.
例如，暴力也许是战斗，也许是杀戮。
And usually that involves blood or something rather rather horrible sometimes disturbing we could say.
通常这涉及血液或相当可怕的东西，有时我们可以说令人不安。
The question is do violent video games have a negative effect on youth.
问题是暴力电子游戏对青少年有负面影响吗？
OK a negative effect.
好的负面影响。
That means a bad effect.
这意味着不好的影响。
So when we're talking about very young people like kids should they be allowed to play violent video
因此，当我们谈论像孩子这样的非常年轻的人时，是否应该允许他们播放暴力视频
games.
游戏。
If they do well they'd be negatively affected or not affected.
如果他们做得好，他们会受到负面影响或不受影响。
And that's the debate when to look first at the side that says hey actually this is a really bad thing.
这就是何时首先看到说嘿实际上这是一件非常糟糕的事情的一方的争论。
We should not allow very young people to play violent video games.
我们不应该让非常年轻的人玩暴力电子游戏。
Then we'll look at the opposite view.
然后我们来看相反的观点。
And again we're going to try to use some of the things we learned early on in this lesson.
再一次，我们将尝试使用我们在本课早期学到的一些东西。
All right.
好的。
So this is the side that says yes yes video games have a negative effect.
所以这就是说电子游戏有负面影响的一面。
Bad effect.
效果不好。
It goes without saying that children are far more likely to learn behaviors from their environment than
毋庸置疑，儿童从环境中学习行为的可能性远大于
adults or older teens.
成人或年龄较大的青少年。
It goes without saying that means it's very obviously true.
不用说，这意味着它很明显是正确的。
If you want to say something is very obviously obviously true.
如果你想说的话，很明显很明显是真的。
You can say it goes without saying that it goes without saying that summer is warmer than winter.
你可以说夏天比冬天更温暖是不言而喻的。
It goes without saying that children are far more likely to learn behaviors from their environment.
不用说，孩子更有可能从他们的环境中学习行为。
That means the things around them your environment is what's around you from your environment than adults
这意味着他们周围的事物你的环境是你周围的事物而不是成年人
or older teens.
或年龄较大的青少年。
So maybe what we're talking about here when we say youth are young people very very young people like
所以当我们说青年是年轻人时，也许我们在这里谈论的是非常非常年轻的人喜欢
children or maybe people in their early teens 13 maybe 14 years old.
孩子或者可能是 13 岁或 14 岁的青少年。
So it stands to reason that if children are exposed to violent games at a young age they may begin to
因此，如果孩子在很小的时候接触到暴力游戏，他们可能会开始
see violence as a solution to their problems just like it is in games.
就像在游戏中一样，将暴力视为解决问题的方法。
OK exposed if we use the word exposed it means you're around that a lot if you're exposed to violence.
好吧，如果我们使用“暴露”这个词，这意味着如果你暴露在暴力之下，你就会经常出现这种情况。
That means you see a lot of violence.
这意味着你会看到很多暴力。
They're exposed to very good things that means maybe you will begin to actually learn and do those good
他们接触到非常好的事情，这意味着也许你会开始真正学习并做好这些事情
things.
事物。
We can say exposed to the sun exposed just means you're around that.
我们可以说暴露在阳光下只是意味着你在那个地方。
Stands to reason is a way to say similar to this.
按理说是一种类似于此的说法。
It's obvious but it's very reasonable to say this stands to reason is often a way to say it is reasonable
很明显，但说这很有道理，这通常是一种说它是合理的方式
that.
那。
OK so it stands to reason it's just a common phrase that we use when we're having discussions making
好的，所以这是有道理的，这只是我们在讨论时使用的常用短语
points and especially when we're trying to convince other people to agree with us may begin to see violence
特别是当我们试图说服其他人同意我们的观点时，可能会开始看到暴力
as a solution to their problems.
作为他们问题的解决方案。
A solution to your problems would be how you deal with your problems how you solve your problems.
解决您的问题s将是你如何处理你的问题你如何解决你的问题。
Here's a problem.
这是一个问题。
Oh if I just punch this person or kill this person that will solve my problem because that's what I
哦，如果我只是打这个人或杀死这个人，这将解决我的问题，因为这就是我
learned in games.
在游戏中学习。
That's what it's saying here.
这就是它在这里所说的。
Just like it is in games because it is in games.
就像在游戏中一样，因为它在游戏中。
You have to kill the bad guys in order to win.
你必须杀死坏人才能获胜。
So the basic argument here is the rules of video games are kill bad people win.
所以这里的基本论点是电子游戏的规则是杀坏人赢。
And the argument is if kids play a lot of violent games then they're going to see everything like that
争论的焦点是，如果孩子们玩很多暴力游戏，那么他们就会看到这样的一切
kill people win or do violence win beat people win.
杀人赢或施暴赢打人赢。
OK.
好的。
That's the basic point.
这是基本点。
Here's an analogy an analogy would be the way ink shows up more clearly on a white cloth.
这是一个类比，一个类比是墨水在白布上更清晰地显示的方式。
So again we're trying to help the audience or the other side very clearly visualize or see our point
所以我们再次试图帮助观众或对方非常清楚地想象或看到我们的观点
and we can use analogies to do that.
我们可以使用类比来做到这一点。
They have a white cloth and you drop some blue ink some red ink on the white cloth.
他们有一块白布，你在白布上滴一些蓝色墨水和一些红色墨水。
It'll be very vivid on the white cloth if you drop it on a brown cloth.
如果你把它放在棕色布上，它会在白布上非常生动。
It won't be as vivid.
它不会那么生动。
That is to say maybe young people children are more pure.
也就是说，也许年轻人孩子更纯洁。
They're pure.
他们是纯洁的。
And so whatever they are exposed to at a young age they will be very impacted by that.
所以无论他们在年轻时接触到什么，他们都会受到很大的影响。
It will be like ink showing up on a very pure white cloth.
就像墨水出现在非常纯净的白布上。
It's more pure so the effect is stronger.
它更纯净，因此效果更强。
Isn't it true.
是不是真的。
Remember this expression we used.
记住我们使用的这个表达式。
We want to ask the other side to say yes we want them to agree.
我们想请对方说是的，我们希望他们同意。
Isn't it true that kids are more impressionable than adults impressionable means that they're more likely
不是说孩子比成年人更易受影响吗？ 易受影响意味着他们更有可能
to be affected.
受到影响。
It's more likely that whatever they are exposed to they will do those things or be more likely to do
无论他们接触什么，他们更有可能会做这些事情或更有可能做
those things.
那些事。
Or it's like saying the ink is going to show up more brightly or more vividly on the white cloth and
或者就像说墨水会在白布上呈现得更鲜艳或更生动，
there the white cloth very impressionable.
那里的白布非常易受影响。
Oh I see everyone around me being very polite so I will do the same thing because I'm very young I'm
哦，我看到我周围的每个人都非常有礼貌，所以我会做同样的事情，因为我还很年轻
more likely to do that.
更有可能这样做。
OK hopefully all that's clear this is I think a reasonable argument on one side.
好的，希望一切都清楚，这是我认为一方面是合理的论点。
Now let's look at the other side and see how the other side deals with this argument saying that violent
现在让我们看看对方，看看对方如何处理这种说法，说暴力
video games are a negative thing for very young people.
电子游戏对非常年轻的人来说是一件消极的事情。